<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Nelson Portifolio</title>
    <link>/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Nelson Portifolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:11:53 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological Database</title>
      <link>/post/biological-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:11:53 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/biological-classification/</guid>
      <description>GBIF provides very large datasets of biological beings. I downloaded a dataset and implemented some infrastructure to present it in the browser. The dataset had 7 million entries. I grouped them into 757 entries. I developed a Restful API to provide the data through HTTP protocol and a ReactApp that may consume it. Currently, everything is deployed in Heroku. The Link to the site is here. Deployment is under free account so loading is a bit slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triangulation</title>
      <link>/post/triangulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 12:12:33 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/triangulation/</guid>
      <description>Delaunay triangulation is a special triangulation, where the circumcircle of any triangle in the triangulation does not contain any vertex in its interior. L&amp;rsquo;idée was proposed in 1934 by Boris Delaunay in his paper Sur la Sphère Vide [1]. The triangulation&amp;rsquo;s emptiness property maximizes the smallest interior angle of the triangles in the triangulation and has important applications to several areas, including mesh generation.
A robust C-language implementation of mesh generation and refinement that applies Delaunay triangulation is Triangle, made by Jonathan Richard Shewchuk in 1996: Engineering a 2D Quality Mesh Generator and Delaunay Triangulator [2].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>